Abiodun Olonade

(+234) 70-1510-9571 / (+234) 80-3282-7281 emmanuel_olonade@yahoo,com https://www.linkedin.com/in/abiodun-olonade/ Transit village 2, Adetokunbo Ademola Street, Victoria island, Lagos state.

Graduate of Electronics and Electrical Engineering with a major in Communication engineering. Highly organized and resourceful entry-level front-end developer with a superb work ethic, engineering and coding background. Seeking to leverage my 5+ years' programming skills as a Junior Software Engineer.

I am a passionate front-end web developer with 3years+ of learning experience using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and React JS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for web apps.

SKILLS

- Effective communicator
- Decision-maker and Problem solver
- Critical and Analytical Thinking
- Eager to learn

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Git/GitHub

- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel
- Power point.
- Outlook
- WordPress

GITHUB REPOSITORY - https://github.com/SlimPapii

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE - https://abiodun-olonade.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Graduated 04/2022

Bachelor of Technology, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology – Ogbomoso, Oyo State.

- Major in Electronics and Electrical Engineering
- Coursework: Communication Engineering
- Member of Nigeria society of engineers (Graduate member)
- Grade: Second Class Upper
- Independently worked on a biometric smart attendance system and also developed an efficient web application to monitor the attendance system.

Graduated 08/2013

Secondary School Certificate (SSC), Educational Legacy College – Ibadan, Oyo State.

- Science Department
- West African Senior School Certificate Examination (WASSCE) certified
- National Examination Council (NECO) certified

RELATED EXPERIENCE

02/2021 - Present

Volunteer, BEESTECH – Ibadan, Oyo State.

- Created more than 5 web application with HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Used CSS media queries/Bootstrap to design multiple responsive web apps
- Created, maintained, and enforced front-end code and documentation standards (readable codes)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

08/2022 - Present

Procurement Analyst, NoemDek Limited - Ikoyi, Lagos State.

- Procured and managed supply of materials, products and financial performance of products and maintained clients
- Determining supply needs and researching potential suppliers.
- Acting as a liaison and communicating pricing and performance needs to vendors and suppliers.
- Sourcing suppliers and testing product samples.
- Documenting the features and benefits of products and services.
- Preparing cost-benefit analysis reports for review by managers.
- Negotiating favourable procurement contracts with selected vendors and suppliers.
- Documenting processes and generating monthly supply cost reports.
- Monitoring the company's demand for products to avoid supply shortages.
- Keeping abreast of vendor and supplier-related activities in the industry.
- Generating reports in appropriate format using basic software. Reviews to ensure accuracy and completeness. Identify issues (e.g., missing variables, incorrect data, etc.)
- Monitor MOQs and Procurement/Supplier related inventory policies to optimize inventory and minimize obsolescence.

08/2020 - 12/2020

Field Maintenance Engineer (FME) Intern, HUAWEI TECHNOLOGY.CO.NIG LTD – Lekki-epe, Lagos State.

- Airtel managed service telecommunication engineer
- Effectively and efficiently maintaining the BTS and Access Radio Network; ensuring the overall network availability meets the pre-set targets as laid out by the management, taking into cognizance the platinum, gold, silver and bronze sites are all placed in order of priorities.
- Efficient resolution of all Network Faults (Power outages, Transmission Access Radio & BTS failures) ensuring that the average downtime of 6 hours for MTTR is maintained.
- Troubleshooting and configuration of Node B on both ATM and IP RAN link.
- Proffer solutions to repetitive BSS network problems affecting network quality and availability on all BSS Platform as assigned.
- Installation & Maintenance of the BTS and transmission equipment.
- Site configuration in accordance with Installation Specifications.

05/2016 - 03/2018

Electrician Intern, SIR KAY Electrical works - Ibadan, Oyo State.

- Installs conduits and pipes to house electrical wires and cables
- Installing, maintaining, and repairing electrical control, wiring, and lighting systems.
- Performing general electrical maintenance.

- Inspecting circuit breakers, and other electrical components.

 Troubleshooting electrical issues using appropriate testing devices.

 Repairing and replacing equipment, electrical wiring, and fixtures.
- Performing circuit breaker corrective maintenance.